Arpit Goel

Data Specialist involved in Data Driven Business Decisions.

Delhi NCR, India civil.arpit@gmail.com +919212455566

Experienced in Different Projects by using Machine Learning Algorithms and interpreting their results using Visualizations and graphs. Done Exploratory Data Analysis, and Predictive Analysis as part of Real-Live Industrial Internship Projects along with giving approaches towards implementation. Worked as Team Lead in Product Engineering Department of a B2B SAAS Startup with the role inclined towards Product Optimization and Product Enhancement. Sound Knowledge of Python, R, Tableau, SQL, MS-Excel. Determined to Learn and Apply Artificial Intelligence and Deep Learning. Efficient in Predictive Analytics and Descriptive Analytics.

Personal Details

Date of Birth: 1993-05-25 Eligible to work in: India

Highest Career Level: 2-5 years experience

Industry: Banking & Finance, Education & Instruction, Human Resources, Internet, Ecommerce, KPO, Research, Analytics, Marketing, Other, Project Management, Sales, Software Development, Technology

Work Experience

Data Analyst

GenLeap Ecosystems Pvt Ltd May 2021 to Present

Being a part of Bootstrap Startup, Involved in Data Analysis and Data Visualization. Playing major role in developing an algorithm for calculation of Astromancy scores by an Astrological Calculation Engine using Rest API and Python with process efficient approach. Involved in design of Data Warehouse Architecture using GCP & BigQuery.

Intern Data Scientist - Product Engineering Department

Slintel

January 2021 to April 2021

- 1. Project: Analysis of Salesforce CRM data to derive useful insights for Slintel. This Project was inclined towards analyzing the Salesforce CRM Data of our clients to find Insights for Product Optimization. As a result of analysis, found KPIs which helped in restructuring the Leads Database by mitigation of obsene leads and also Product feature enhancement KPIs which can be used to make a prediction system similar to Einstein Score and Pardot Score which are native systems of Salesforce.
- 2. Project: Recalculation of Technographics Confidence Score. This Project was taken up as an experiment to find out the outcomes of an approach being applied as a POC for Recalculation of confidences using machine learning, predictive analytics and mathematical and statistical approaches. Using Clustering Algorithm, data was clustered into the groups on the behalf of no. of domains and

recency which were leveraged with prominent weightages replacing the earlier weightages based on random mathematical calculation. Overall we succeeded to segment with transition from Heuristic segmentation approach towards automated Scientific Segmentation approach with greater confidence lift towards technographics scoring.

Intern Data Scientist

BCG GAMMA

March 2021 to March 2021

Mar 2021 - Mar 2021 (1 month)

Badge of completion for the Open-Access Data Science & Advanced Analytics Virtual Experience Program has been awarded.

Works Include:

- 1.Business Understanding & Problem Framing.
- 2. Exploratory Data Analysis & Data Cleaning.
- 3. Feature Engineering.
- 4. Modeling & Evaluation.
- 5.Insights & Recommendation.

Intern Data Scientist

Ouantium

December 2020 to March 2021

Over the period of December 2020 to March 2021, completed practical task module in: Data preparation and customer analytics.

Intern Data Scientist

ANZ

December 2020 to March 2021

Dec 2020 - Mar 2021 (4 months)

Over the period of December 2020 to March 2021, I completed practical task modules in:

Exploratory Data Analysis

Predictive Analytics

Data Analytics Consulting Virtual Internship

KPMG India

October 2020 to December 2020

Over the period of October 2020 to December 2020, I have completed practical task modules in:

Data Quality Assessment

Data Insights

Data Insights and Presentation

Intern Data Scientist

JPMorgan Chase & Co

August 2020 to December 2020

Over the period of August 2020 to December 2020, I have completed practical task modules in:

Interface with a stock price data feed

Use JPMorgan Chase frameworks and tools

Display data visually for traders

Freelance Executive - MIS

Bright Concepts November 2019 to July 2020

Education

M.Tech in Data Science & Engineering (WILP)

Birla Institute of Technology & Science - Pilani, Rajasthan November 2021 to Present

PG Program - WILP Program in Big Data , Data Science , Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning

November 2020 to Present

Master Certification in BIG Data Engineering

TrendyTech EdTech Institute
September 2021 to November 2021

Master Certification in Data Analytics

Simplilearn Edtech Institute July 2020 to January 2021

Bachelor's in Technology

Manav Rachna International University - Faridabad, Haryana July 2011 to November 2015

Skills / IT Skills

- · Data Analysis
- Data Visualization
- · Machine Learning
- Excel
- Tableau
- Sql
- Python
- Hadoop
- Apache Spark
- Mongodb
- Big Data Analytics
- Hive
- Scala

Languages

• English - Fluent

• Hindi - Fluent

Online Profile

http://linkedin.com/in/scientistarpit

Certifications and Licenses

Microsoft AI Classroom Series

October 2020 to Present

Certification Program in Data Science by Lets Upgrade

November 2020 to Present

Python For Data Science By IBM

December 2020 to Present

R Programming for Data Science by IBM

September 2020 to Present